<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jalan-jalan</title><link href="http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/</id><updated>2014-10-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Back in Taiwan, after 4 years</title><link href="http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/2014/10/18/back-in-taiwan-after-4-years/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-10-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Lintang JP</name></author><id>tag:travel.theprasojos.web.id,2014-10-18:2014/10/18/back-in-taiwan-after-4-years/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been a long time since I abandon this blog and continue to write on my other blog ( which I also kinda abandon it as well when I discovered lots of new things on internet about this free CMS under google apps, which then leap me back to this blog ). My last post on this blog was in 2010, that was so 4 years a go, and where was I last 4 years ago ? Taiwan :). I remember landed here 4 years a go exactly at the same date, 19th October 2010. That was my very first international breakthrough integration projects. Yes, my first real international integration project on telecommunication industries if I may say so, because the previous one in 2007 did not actually a telecom project. It was mere an IT project where the company I work for was hired to build a web portal for an operator in Malaysia, but still, it's a web portal, it's IT, not Telecom :). First international project, alone, in a country where they don't use english on their daily live activities, what a combination. And also, that was my first year on ///, what experience do you expect from someone that just handling few telecom nodes with not-so-much experience ? Well, luckily for me, for that 2 months there, everything seem to go well. I got a lots of help from the local team, from my home base team, and also from prays that never stops from my family of course :) I learned a lots of new things, new techniques, new details that I never think of before. And what's better from all that ? I make new friends and new colleagues from around the globe. And now, 4 years later, I have moved to another country but still at the same company, and thankfully they still remember me, and invited me to come over again for another project. I really don't think this is fully because of my knowledge. I was a newbie 4 years a go, what knowledge and experience do you expect from that ? I believe this is more because of the relationship that I built with them for these past years. In Islam we call it Silaturahim, maintaining the relationship with everyone that has been worked with you. This is something I really learn from my past. I know I have let down some people by not finishing the projects they gave me when I was still in college. And I also remember some projects I couldn't finish during my first transition during the graduation and move to Jakarta. I still remember that all, and it will always be my reference to not do that again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;From Abu Hurayrah radi &amp;#39;anhu, he said, &amp;quot;I heard the Prophet Sallallaahu&amp;#39; Alaihi Wa Sallam said, &amp;#39;Whoever wants his sustenance expanded and their age extended , he shall maintain his relationship with his friends&amp;quot; (HR. Al-Bukhari no. 5986 and Muslim no. 2557).
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="Tips"></category></entry><entry><title>Zimbabwe, part 2..</title><link href="http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/2014/08/02/zimbabwe-part-2/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-08-02T18:13:00+01:00</updated><author><name>onty</name></author><id>tag:travel.theprasojos.web.id,2014-08-02:2014/08/02/zimbabwe-part-2/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, I always put in my pray during Ramadhan, hoping that I can spend the
Ied Al Fitr celebration together with my family, but it turns out that
Allah gave me 'another' new family here in Zimbabwe :). Yes, I spend Ied
Al Fitr here with the big family of Indonesian citizens ( well, not that
big, only 40 people here&amp;nbsp;including the kids ... ). The preparation day
started with making and cooking Ketupat lebaran together..after searched
in youtube, I finally created my very first Ketupat :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="CAM01606" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/cam01606.jpg?w=180" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feels like&amp;nbsp;home with the family.&amp;nbsp;We close the day with&amp;nbsp;ifthaar together
at the embassy office. After isya' in Masjid Al-Abbas on Boeing street,
we got confirmation that the moon has been seen on South Africa, that
means it should be visible in Harare too, so the next day will be the
1st of Syawal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ied prayer started around 8.15. We went to Arcadia mosque, where we met
most of Indonesian people there. I went together within the same car
with the embassy staff. Here's our selfie picture from inside the car :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/cam01613.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Ied pray, everybody gathered around outside the mosque. They
provided some snacks and drinks for free for everybody in the mosque.
It's time for halal bihalal. I even met some Indonesian people I haven't
met before, Dr Widi and his family. They drove from Bulawayo directly to
Harare specially to celebrate the Ied al Fitr together with Indonesian
people in Harare :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/cam01609.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that day continued as usual, since it's Monday. No official holiday
for me :). It's different with in Indonesia, it's like nothing big going
on that day, it's just normal day, business as usual. That is 1 major
difference in celebrating Ied Al Fitr far away from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/cam01618.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, it's time to go back to Jakarta, and celebrate the Ied Al Fitr
together with my family. Happy belated Ied Al Fitr to all Muslims in the
world :)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Zimbabwe part 1..</title><link href="http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/2014/07/19/zimbabwe-part-1/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-19T21:13:00+01:00</updated><author><name>onty</name></author><id>tag:travel.theprasojos.web.id,2014-07-19:2014/07/19/zimbabwe-part-1/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Chance&amp;nbsp;to see the outside world is one of my reason to take&amp;nbsp;this job :).
Never ever crossed&amp;nbsp;in my mind before that I will visit this country. I
have heard about this country before &amp;nbsp;when economic crisis hit this
country around 2008. &amp;nbsp;1 trillion&amp;nbsp;dollar zimbabwe equals to 1 USD, such
an epic story. My impression first time I hit this country is that, it
looks like&amp;nbsp;Indonesia, on 1970's :) ( don't get me wrong, I see 1970's
picture of Indonesia in some&amp;nbsp;old movie, I wasn't born yet that day :p ).
If you see the buses, the people, and how the city looks like, then you
might end up with the same conclusion with me :D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/2014-06-20-13-52-22.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No pic hoax ? Here's one of the picture I took during my journey from
hotel to /// office. Unfortunately I don't have the picture for the old
buses (updated), but you can imagine inter-city bus, with full of bag
loaded on top of it. Yeah, one of the problem here is transportation.
Those buses seem to only pass once in a few hour. Once they passed,
there will be so many people waiting, together with their belongings. I
also see some people waive their hands on the streets looking for a car
lift. Not sure if it is safe to give them a lift, since I'm just a
foreigner here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---- Updated&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the bus view in Harare..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/cam01478.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait, there's also tall building here in this country :). During my
first week here, /// put me on Crowne plaza hotel located on the city
centre, surrounded by few tall buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/2014-06-15-17-01-26.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See ? Not too bad, except the internet speed :D. I can only really
browse the internet on 5-6 AM in the morning. When I came back to hotel
from the office around 7-8, the internet speed is horrible. I waited so
long to open a webpage ( which then ended up with me closing the laptop
and go to sleep :p). Yeah, the infrastructure is not good here.
Telecommunications and Transportation, those 2 things need to be
improved first here before they want to go to the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--- Updated, here's the other city view of Harare..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/cam01484.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the good thing about this country is that, there's almost no
traffic jam :). We can go to the airport from /// office in about 30
minutes on daytime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/2014-06-25-08-51-41.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wider road with less cars, compare this to Jakarta :). And yes, I rarely seen
any motor bikes here, which is probably a good thing :D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the other good thing, Indonesia has its embassy here. So, I went
there to meet with the people and to introduce myself. It's good to have
Indonesian friends in this nowhere country :D, at least I can speak
bahasa again after so long. Feels like home, but not the real home :).
The embassy staff are very helpful, if you imagine that all government
officers are hard, rigid, then you are wrong. They are all very friendly
here. I went there almost every weekend, just to say hi, and to talk to
them. &amp;nbsp;And yes, they held a friendly 17an match to celebrate Indonesia's
independence day, where &amp;nbsp;I won Gaple match, with pak Tachsin Fernandi as
my co-player....:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/2014-06-21-16-19-29.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's only about 40 Indonesian people here in Zimbabwe, including the kids.
Not so much, but that makes them&amp;nbsp;big family together in a foreign
country :) If you are interested more, just invite their Facebook
account &amp;quot;Perwakin Harare&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, that is all for part 1, time to go back to the apartment and prepare
some meal for Ifthar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zimbabwe, July 19th, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="embassy"></category><category term="harare"></category><category term="indonesian embassy"></category><category term="zimbabwe"></category></entry><entry><title>Ireland VISA</title><link href="http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/2014/03/23/ireland-visa/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-23T20:48:00+00:00</updated><author><name>onty</name></author><id>tag:travel.theprasojos.web.id,2014-03-23:2014/03/23/ireland-visa/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bismillahirrahmaanirrahiim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- spotify.start();
-- ehh, yovie and nuno, sebingkai rindu buat mentari :D, jadi inget
good old days di pojokan kantor gedung operator kedua (saat itu) di
Indonesia :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yak, setelah dapet konfirmasi #selamat anda diterima#, dimulailah
perjalanan mengurus VISA :). Karena ini adalah VISA kerja, maka
persyaratan utamannya adalah dokumen kontrak kerja dan greencard. Kalau
lihat2 di web nya citizensinformation.ie, ada 2 tipe visa kerja, yaitu
working permit VISA dan greencard. Salah satu perbedaan mencoloknya
adalah kalau greencard boleh langsung bawa keluarga saat itu juga,
sedangkan kalo working permit hanya boleh bawa keluarga setelah 1 tahun
disana. Penantian dimulai dari menunggu dengan harap-harap cemas kapan
greencard nya dateng dengan selamat. Gak lama ( surprise juga ) ada
paketan dari DHL isinya greencard. Oooo ini toh yg namanya greencard,
kirain kartu yg warnanya ijo :p, ternyata selembar surat A4 warna
putih-kekuning-kuningan :D. Disitu ada informasi nama sesuai passport,
foto, nomer greencard, weekly salary *ups, dll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nah, karena ini employment VISA, silakan liat link persyaratannya disini
:
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.inis.gov.ie/en/INIS/Pages/Employment%20or%20Intra-company%20Transfer,%20Scientific%20Researcher,%20Training,%20Van%20Der%20Elst"&gt;http://www.inis.gov.ie/en/INIS/Pages/Employment%20or%20Intra-company%20Transfer,%20Scientific%20Researcher,%20Training,%20Van%20Der%20Elst&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iya, linknya gak SEO friendly, ada %20 nya, mungkin servernya windows
ya, ups :D
Anyway..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flownya nanti gini :
1. Isi form online
2. Submit hard copy document yang dibutuhin. Semua hardcopy di copy rangkap 2.
3. Tunggu seminggu kalo syarat2nya dah ok insyaAllah jadi deh.
4. Sebenernya fee VISA Ireland buat Indonesia ini gratis, namun karena
sebenernya di Indonesia ga ada kedutaan langsung Irlandia ( adanya
honorary consul ), maka semua dokumen yang hard copy tadi akan dikirim
ke Irlandia oleh honorary consul Jakarta ( yang tepatnya di BEJ lt.12,
kantor pengacara Roosdiono and partners ). Nah, jadinya ada 'VISA fee',
terakhir biayanya Rp 550.000,- per permohonan VISA :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nih, saya pastein persyaratan lengkap dari web mereka, beserta
penjelasan yg saya tau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Fully complete the online application form, and submit your signed
summary application form, photographs and fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di website nya inis.gov.ie itu ada link buat isi form online, disini
:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.visas.inis.gov.ie/avats/OnlineHome.aspx"&gt;https://www.visas.inis.gov.ie/avats/OnlineHome.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silakan diisi dulu, sebaiknya persiapkan juga passport dan dokumen
greencard anda, karena nanti ada referensi tentang nomer-nomer tersebut
yg harus diisikan.
2. In addition to the signed summary application form, please also
submit a signed letter of application&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;outlining your reason for wishing to visit Ireland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;giving details of any members of your family who are currently in
Ireland, or any other EU State.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stating how long you plan to stay,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;undertaking that you will observe the conditions of your visa, that
you will not become a burden on the State, and that you will leave
the State on the expiry of your permission to remain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nah, setelah isi form online, ini termasuk salah satu dokumen yang harus
diserahkan secara hard copy ke honorary consulate. Bikin aja surat
pernyataan (in english :p) yang menyatakan bahwa, saya, nama, bla bla,
nomer pasport sekian-sekian, ingin mengurus VISA untuk keperluan xxxx,
karena telah memperoleh green card dengan nomor yyyy yang berlaku sampai
dengan YYYY/MM/DD. Saya berjanji mematuhi ketentuan yang berlaku dan
tidak akan menjadi beban bagi negara. Udah deh.. rangkai kata-katanya,
trus print :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Passport, valid for 12 months, and copy of previous passport if
applicable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ini ga usah dijelasin kali ya, paspor harus masih berlaku minimal 12
bulan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. If you have been refused a visa for any other country, details of
this must be given. Submit the original letter issued to you by the
authorities of that country. Concealment of visa refusals will result in
your Irish visa application being refused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ini juga jelas, kalau pernah ditolak VISA negara manapun, silakan di
declare, daripada ntar ketauan pas di pintu imigrasi, ga lucu juga baru
dateng suruh balik kan :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. A detailed statement of your bank account covering a six-month period
immediately prior to your visa application, and showing sufficient funds
to cover your costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nah, ini maksudnya rekening koran bank. Saya kemaren 3 bulan aja cukup
kok. Bisa rekening koran, bisa juga yg di buku tabungan itu di foto kopi
untuk semua transaksi 3 bulan ke belakang.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6. Valid Work Permit / Intra-Company Transfer Permit. Medical Doctors
please note: not all non-EEA doctors require an employment permit to
work in Ireland. See &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.inis.gov.ie/en/INIS/Pages/WP10000012"&gt;http://www.inis.gov.ie/en/INIS/Pages/WP10000012&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djei.ie/labour/workpermits/doctors.htm"&gt;http://www.djei.ie/labour/workpermits/doctors.htm&lt;/a&gt; for further
information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nah, ini maksudnya greencard tadi. Copy dan sertakan dalam form hardcopy
yg di submit, inget, rangkap 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="7"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employment Contract (if any)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8. Letter from employer in Ireland confirming details of the job you
will take up and the salary you will be paid. If accommodation is being
provided by your employer details of this should also be given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ini juga jelas, kontrak kerja. Biasanya dikirim jadi satu sama green
card nya. Kalau case saya, mereka kirim kontrak kerja dulu buat
ditandatanganin, terus saya harus kirim lagi balik ke mereka. Di dalam
kontrak kerja juga biasanya disebutin akomodasi apa yang akan disediain
sama pihak employer, dll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9. Evidence of qualifications and previous work experience in this area
may be requested by the visa officer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nah, kalau kasus saya, ini kira-2 seperti surat referensi kerja lah,
dari employer2 kita sebelumnya. Kasih fotokopiannya aja, rangkap 2 semua
ya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O ya, selain dokumen diatas, waktu itu saya juga lampirkan rencana
flight sama hotel tempat menginap. Untuk rencana flight dan hotel,
caranya gini :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Flight, buka aja website etihad atau emirates, atau apapun maskapai
yg punya penerbangan ke Dublin. Isi rencana perjalanan ( tanggal ga
pasti juga gpp kok, kan belum tau VISA nya jadinya kapan, yang jelas
harus reasonable aja, kira2 3-4 minggu lagi gitu ). Sampai ke halaman
konfirmasi, stop, langsung print screen. Yang mereka butuhin cuma
capture rencana perjalanan dan transit aja. Ga perlu sampe booking tiket
pesawat dulu kok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Hotel, kemaren saya pake&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.irelandhotels.com"&gt;http://www.irelandhotels.com&lt;/a&gt;, pastikan anda
pilih hotel yang bisa di book dengan kartu kredit, dan CANCELLATION nya
gratis ! kenapa ? karena case saya, hotel disediain kantor, tapi harus
pesen sendiri dulu, dan saya ngga akan pesen sebelum VISA jadi :p.
Jadiii, book aja di irelandhotels tadi, pilih hotel mana yang bisa di
CANCEL GRATIS. Selesai book, mereka biasanya kita akan dapet email, nah,
silakan di print tuh. Kalo udah di print, silakan cancel bookingan tadi
:D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nah, udah deh, persyaratan udah lengkap. O ya, jangan lupa juga cetak
pas foto ukuran paspor, tepatnya 4.5 x 5.5, dimana wajah kita tampak 80%
dalam foto tersebut. Backgroundnya putih. Biasanya kalo dateng ke tempat
cetak foto besar, mereka pasti tau ukurannya kalo langsung disebutin
buat VISA gitu.. Foto sediain 2 lembar, lebih juga boleh buat nanti
ngurus2 disini (perjalanan masih panjang loh, VISA ini kan hanya buat
masuk aja ke Ireland, ntar sampai disini ngurus kartu GNIB sama Re-Entry
VISA lagi, dan butuh foto, mending bawa dari Jakarta ). Dan jangan lupa,
semua dokumen yg hardcopy, di copy 2x, karena yg satu set akan dikirim
ke konsulat di Singapore, dan set lainnya akan disimpan di kantor
honorary consul Jakarta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O ya, sekalian, ini nomer dan alamat Ireland honorary consul yang di
Jakarta. Good luck :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Sinta Roosdiono&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Consulate of Ireland, Indonesia
Indonesia Stock Exchange Building, Tower I, 12th Floor
Jl. Jend. Sudirman Kav. 52-53. Jakarta 12190
Ph&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="reference external" href="tel:%2B6221%20515%201977"&gt;+6221 515 1977&lt;/a&gt;
Fax&amp;nbsp;&lt;a class="reference external" href="tel:%2B6221%20515%201977"&gt;+6221 515 1977&lt;/a&gt;
Office hours: 9.30am - 12am and 2pm - 4pm&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
</summary><category term="Green Card"></category><category term="Ireland"></category><category term="VISA"></category></entry><entry><title>Daddy's trip #1, Medan, part 2</title><link href="http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/2009/12/25/daddys-trip-1-medan-part-2/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-12-25T15:08:00+00:00</updated><author><name>onty</name></author><id>tag:travel.theprasojos.web.id,2009-12-25:2009/12/25/daddys-trip-1-medan-part-2/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;ok, part 2 dimulai...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karena emang trip nya udah lama, jadinya nulis blog ini sambil liat
foto-foto dulu, baru deh ceritanya diketik :). Perjalanan berikutnya
adalah keliling-keliling kota medan. Baru tau juga ya, ternyata ada
stasiun kereta api di medan, dikirain cuman ada di jawa doang, he he.
Karena motonya sambil di dalam taksi dengan kecepatan tinggi, gambarnya
jadi agak blur deh. Tapi gpp, yang penting kan essensinya :p, intinya di
medan ternyata ada stasiun kereta juga ya?he he.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lalu, sempat ambil juga foto-foto sudut-sudut kota Medan. Banyak juga
bangunan-bangunan lama yang masih kokoh berdiri. Kalau di jakarta
seperti di daerah stasiun kota lah. Atau kalau di Surabaya seperti di
daerah semut atau jagalan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Medan Street 1" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/dsc00408.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh ya, dua gambar ini ngambil gambarnya sambil naik becak loh, bukan
becak motor, tapi becak sepeda. Jadi gambarnya nggak kehalang kaca
kendaraan..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Medan Street 2" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/dsc00411.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sempat jalan juga ke Merdeka Walk. Sebuah tempat yang penuh dengan
makanan dan warung tenda. Di situ juga ada lapangan seperti alun-alun,
yang -kata pak sopir- sering dipake konser kalo ada artis-artis ibukota.
Merdeka walk ini letaknya di tengah kota. Sayang, gambar yang diambil
agak kabur karena diambil dari mobil, dan karena malam hari, kurang
pencahayaan, maklum..modal HP doang buat ambil fotonya, he he.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Medan Street" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/dsc00416.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kalau hari pertama dan kedua nginepnya di Tiara Medan, hari ke tiga dan
keempat nginepnya di Grand Angkasa. Ini terjadi karena ada kejadian
tidak terduga, he he. Well, baguslah, jadi bisa ngerasain 2 hotel
sekaligus deh. Hotel Grand Angkasa ini kelasnya sepertinya lebih tinggi
dari hotel Tiara. Letaknya sepertinya cukup strategis, di sudut sebuah
persimpangan, tepatnya jalan Dr. Sutomo. Di depan hotel ini terdapat
sebuah universitas yang *dulu* katanya cukup terkenal di Medan, yaitu
Universitas Nomensen. Ruangan hotel menurutku bagus, ada broadband
internet (ini yang penting buat nelpon via voip ke rumah, he he).
Sepertinya pake speedy atau astinet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Sebuah mobil di depan grand angkasa" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/dsc00414x.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Sebuah TV layar datar di hotel grand angkasa" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/dsc00420.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selama di Medan, pagi dan siang hari dimanfaatkan untuk jalan-jalan,
dan malamnya ? tentu saja di kantor client, he he. Ok, sekian dulu.
Episode ke 2 adalah perjalanan ke Balikpapan. Tunggu ya....&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="grand angkasa"></category><category term="medan"></category><category term="merdeka walk"></category></entry><entry><title>Daddy's trip #1, Medan</title><link href="http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/2009/12/25/daddys-trip-1-medan/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-12-25T11:35:00+00:00</updated><author><name>onty</name></author><id>tag:travel.theprasojos.web.id,2009-12-25:2009/12/25/daddys-trip-1-medan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Berikut ini serial kisah catatan perjalanan Ayah, dalam rangka urusan
kantor, ke beberapa kota di Indonesia *cieeh, lagak profesional :p.
Bulan November dan Desember ini kebetulan banyak sekali tugas ke luar
kota, jadinya nyempatin ambil foto-foto deh. Jadi ceritanya, business
travel ke medan ini kira-kira tanggal 9-13 November 2009 yang lalu.
Lokasi utama di Medan yaitu seputaran Setia Budi, Cut Mutia,
Sisingamaraja, Merdeka Walk, Lembur Kuring, dan Dr. Sutomo. Mampir juga
ke brastagi, walau hanya beberapa menit langsung cabut, he he. Ok, mari
kita mulai cerita petualangannya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medan, kota yang lumayan panas. Baru dateng di bandara, langsung naik
taksi ke kantor client di daerah Setia Budi *hanya ada satu kantor
disitu, yang ada towernya tinggi, secara disitu daerah perumahan :p.
Disambut oleh taksi bandara yang agak kasar. Entahlah karena bawaan
orang Medan, atau emang lagi apes kebagian supir yang kasar ya ? Yang
jelas waktu itu sang supir bawa mobilnya sambil sedikit menggerutu, dan
kita juga hampir nabrak motor di jalan. Padahal taksi bandara loh, ujung
tombak pariwisata daerah :p. Salah satu alasan yang bikin sang sopir
bete adalah karena kita keluar pas jam pulang sekolah, dan pas jam makan
siang pula, jadi jalanan agak macet. Kulihat ngga separah Jakarta sih
macetnya, gimana kalo si sopir ini hijrah ke Jakarta yah, tambah stress
kali dia. Sampailah di kantor client di daerah SetiaBudi.&amp;nbsp; Setelah
pekerjaan setengah hari itu selesai, kita mampir dulu deh ke sebuah
restoran sunda yang ada di Medan, Lembur Kuring. Restorannya lumayan
gede. Pengunjungnya kebanyakan orang-orang tionghoa, well setidaknya itu
yang kulihat malam itu. Disini kita coba sebuah minuman khas medan...jus
martebe, markisa+terung belanda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Martebe Juice" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/dsc00371x.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" style="width: 300px; height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Martebe Juice
Rasanya yaaa, seperti rasa markisa dicampur terung belanda :p, ada
asemnya dari markisa, manis+asem dari terung belanda. Restoran ini juga
mempunyai kolam ikan yang lumayan besar, kalau ngajak anak-anak kesini,
pasti pada minta liat kolam ini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selesai, langsung deh mengarah ke sebuah hotel di daerah jalan Cut
Mutia. Yap, hotel Tiara medan. Sebuah hotel yang sepertinya sudah agak
tua bangunannya. Lagi di renovasi juga sih, ada tambahan bangunan baru
di sebelahnya. Konon...hotel ini sering jadi langganan keluarga Cendana
kalau mereka lagi ke medan. Kamarnya standar aja, dapet yang double bed.
Internet hanya ada di lobby dengan WiFi. Untungnya dapet kamar lantai 2
yang masih keliatan dari lobby, jadinya masih dapet deh sinyal WiFi nya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Seseorang sedang menunggu di lobby hotel Tiara Medan" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/dsc00376.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seseorang sedang menunggu di lobby hotel Tiara Medan
Esoknya, pilihan tujuan wisata (karena urusan kantor sedang free siang
harinya), adalah brastagi. Berangkat sekitar pukul 09.00, sampai di
brastagi sekitar pukul 12.00. Perjalanan yang lumayan mendaki, menuju
pucak brastagi. Baru tahu juga kalau brastagi itu obyek wisata
pegunungan, he he. Sepanjang perjalanan, beberapa foto sempat diambil,
berikut ini diantaranya. Greenhill city, kurang tau juga ini sebuah
obyek wisata atau komplek perumahan, he he. Yang jelas, kalo ngeliat ada
bianglala raksasa sih, ini tempat tujuan wisata, tapi mungkin masih pagi
ya *sampai sana jam 11.00, jadi mungkin masih sepi pengunjung. Kita
lanjut deh nanjak ke brastagi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Sebuah kincir raksasa di greenhill city" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/dsc00378.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sebuah kincir raksasa di greenhill city
Sepanjang perjalanan menuju brastagi, mengingatkan pada perjalanan
antara Padang dan Bukittinggi. Pinggiran jalan yang hijau dan masih
asri, rumah-rumah penduduk yang sepertinya nyaman sekali-tidak lupa
dengan antena parabola di tiap rumah :D, dan udara yang masih bersih.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Rumah-rumah dengan parabolanya" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/dsc00383.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Sepertinya kantor pemerintahan" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/dsc00384.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sempat mampir juga di sebuah pom bensin menuju brastagi, dengan latar
belakang sebuah gunung, entah gunung apa namanya, ada yang tahu ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Gunung di belakang pom bensin" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/dsc00386.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ada juga pahat-pahatan yang indah di sebuah dinding dalam perjalanan ke
brastagi, nggak sempat turun untuk nanya temanya apa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pahatan dinding" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/dsc00388.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lalu ada juga tugu perjuangan yang berdiri di persimpangan jalan. Kalau ada
yang tahu apa nama tugu ini, pls comment yah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Sebuah tugu perjuangan" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/dsc00389x.jpg?h=70&amp;amp;w=300" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Akhirnya sampai deh di brastagi. Disambut oleh pemandangan keadaan
perkotaan dari atas bukit. Kalau di Malang, mungkin brastagi itu daerah
Pacet nya lah. Banyak orang menawarkan sewa kuda, banyak warung juga
dengan pemandangan yang menarik.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Top view#1" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/dsc00390.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Top view#2" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/dsc00393.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 hari yang lumayan melelahkan, tunggu bagian 2 nya dari episode medan
ini yah, mau jumatan dulu soalnya, he he.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bersambung....&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="brastagi"></category><category term="grand angkasa medan"></category><category term="lembur kuring medan"></category><category term="martebe"></category><category term="tiara medan"></category></entry><entry><title>The Journey began...Part II</title><link href="http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/2008/01/20/the-journey-beganpart-ii/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-01-20T17:31:00+00:00</updated><author><name>onty</name></author><id>tag:travel.theprasojos.web.id,2008-01-20:2008/01/20/the-journey-beganpart-ii/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ok, since mommy wants daddy to continue this post, here comes daddy...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We enter the most important part in our life. It's 14 March 2006, we
held a simple but religious Akad Nikah ceremony that took place on
mommy's family house at Bukittinggi. Actually we planned to held that on
the nearest Mosque around, but it's already late night ( Isya' time was
around 8.00 PM at Bukittinggi ) so our parents decided to held the
ceremony just at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't ask me how nervous I was that time. My hand was so cold and sweat.
My throat also feels bad until I ask Bulek Sur for a glass of water.
Grandpa was also very nervous, his mouth indicating that he praise
Allah's name. Seeing him only made me more nervous :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Nervous.." src="http://lh4.google.com/lintang.jp/R5MhIF0A_vI/AAAAAAAAB04/vAew0sx-Iws/P1040376.JPG?imgmax=512" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nervous..
And, here comes the Akad Nikah, I grab Grandpa Parjono's hand tightly,
and first try was not too good. I'm too nervous for this religious
ceremony. So Grandpa Soenarto ask me to repeat the process.&amp;nbsp; And at the
second time, I finally spoke the whole Akad Nikah words perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Akad Nikah" src="http://lh3.google.com/lintang.jp/R5MhH10A_tI/AAAAAAAAB0o/vYjwhqCt2Zg/akad.jpg?imgmax=512" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Akad Nikah
The second part was my Mas Kawin, which is &amp;quot;hafalan&amp;quot; from&amp;nbsp;a whole surah
of Al-Mulk. Here's the picture :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Mulk" src="http://lh5.google.com/lintang.jp/R5MifV0A_wI/AAAAAAAAB1E/Ni73n9Wz28Y/mulk.jpg?imgmax=512" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mulk
After that, the whole process was completely done. We all can smile out,
alhamdulillah. Finally, we became husband and wife :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Done" src="http://lh4.google.com/lintang.jp/R5MhIF0A_uI/AAAAAAAAB0w/b8C7-WLvv0I/end.JPG?imgmax=512" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Done
We all take a rest then, and prepare for the big day tomorrow for our
wedding party at Dymens Hotel in Bukittinggi. We will post that on part
III :) A day full of smiling, and hand shaking ....&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The Journey began...Part I</title><link href="http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/2008/01/19/the-journey-beganpart-i/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-01-19T14:28:00+00:00</updated><author><name>onty</name></author><id>tag:travel.theprasojos.web.id,2008-01-19:2008/01/19/the-journey-beganpart-i/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's 11 March 2007, when&amp;nbsp;Grandpa and Grandma with auntie Pipot&amp;nbsp;arrived
on Bukittinggi for my marriage. It's&amp;nbsp;3 days before our marriage day.
Before that, Grandma already read a lot about Bukittingi, including it's
famous Nasi kapau. They just can't wait to try it. Arrived on
Minangkabau International Airport, picked up by Mas Didiek and Mbak
Reni. Bukittinggi city is a very cold and fresh city. They spent 3-5
hours for transit and plane flight from Surabaya to Padang. Their
journey then continued about 3 hours (well, that includes lunch at Sate
Mak Syukur in Padang Panjang :D). Finally they arrived at Bukittinggi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 12 March, Grandma and Grandpa want to take a trip around Bukittinggi.
Here's their picture :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="At Bukittinggi's Zoo" src="http://lh6.google.com/lintang.jp/RfZ-SupNsvI/AAAAAAAABFo/u63I2jIk_xw/P1040344.JPG?imgmax=512" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Bukittinggi's Zoo
After that, they visit Jam Gadang. And there they met Mas Didiek and
Mbak Reni. Here's the picture :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Pose at Jam Gadang" src="http://lh4.google.com/lintang.jp/RfZ-XOpNszI/AAAAAAAABGM/VGBPiYyagTY/P1040368.JPG?imgmax=512" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pose at Jam Gadang
Yep, it's quite fun trip. Grandma and Grandpa never been this far from
home until their son married :D After few hours round trip, we finally
back home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's the end of Part I. Mommy will continue the story, daddy is sleepy
right now :D&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Hongkong International Airport</title><link href="http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/2007/06/03/hongkong-international-airport/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-06-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Lintang JP</name></author><id>tag:travel.theprasojos.web.id,2007-06-03:2007/06/03/hongkong-international-airport/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's good to have your laptop travels with you. Like this, in airport, we dont have to be boring while we wait for the plane. Fast connection, provided by PCCW, one of Hongkong's telco operator. Thankyou PCCW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, open YM! messenger, and then open up my office mail....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tadaaa, next assignment, 1. MiTV Malaysia on Monday..(WTF!) 2. STC Saudi Telecom, is this for real ????&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, the plane is boarding, we should get to the plane...
BTW, the picture from our journey will be uploaded soon. For yesterday's photo, you can see it here :
http://picasaweb.google.com/lintang.jp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;originally posted 2/17/07&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>Hongkong survival day #2-1</title><link href="http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/2007/06/03/hongkong-survival-day-2-1/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-06-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Lintang JP</name></author><id>tag:travel.theprasojos.web.id,2007-06-03:2007/06/03/hongkong-survival-day-2-1/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we're lucky. My friend's passport were found. So, yesterday, after finishing the training, we go to the airport to get the passport back.We ride MTR train from Admiralty station to Hongkong central station. After that we changed to Airport Express train.It only took 30 minutes from downtown hongkong to reach airport.That fast ? yep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, the instructor are coming, the training will be start any minutes, I'll stop the blogging and continue later...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;the beauty of java, and the beast of garbage collecting&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;originally posted 2/16/07&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>Hongkong survival day #2-2</title><link href="http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/2007/06/03/hongkong-survival-day-2-2/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-06-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Lintang JP</name></author><id>tag:travel.theprasojos.web.id,2007-06-03:2007/06/03/hongkong-survival-day-2-2/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hongkong is a nice city. I love the mass transportation railway,it's so clean, and of course, definitely fast. Everything is well organized here. I rarely seen any traffic jam in here although the street is not as wide as in Indonesia. Public transportation leave and arrive in time. In this case, who needs private vehicle ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The training was great too. I have a lot question about tuning that answered here, especially in jvm tuning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Btw, you can see my photo here :
http://picasaweb.google.com/lintang.jp/HongkongSurvival&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's for now, catch up with you later.. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;originally posted 2/16/07&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>Hongkong Survival day#1</title><link href="http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/2007/06/03/hongkong-survival-day1/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-06-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Lintang JP</name></author><id>tag:travel.theprasojos.web.id,2007-06-03:2007/06/03/hongkong-survival-day1/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finally, got chance to go abroad outside Indonesia. This is my first journey, to Hongkong. We will be here in 4 days, 2 days training, and 2 days for having fun, he he he. Start from subuh at 04.00 AM to the airport. After clearing customs, we proceed to our plane. We ride China Airlines. As you might guess, all languages, writings, newspapers were in chinese. Dunno, maybe my face looks like a chinese guy. Everytime the stewardess served us, they always said Xiexie to me, but to my friend next to me, they said Thankyou :)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There, we stay at ChaterHouse hotel. Small and warm place. It's weird in hongkong that all building were Ruko, so the first floor used for Shop/Store, and the next floor will be their homeplace as apartment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oya, We spent first day with visiting police station. My friend seems to have problem with his passport, so we go to police station and ask for a memo to gave to Immigration office. But finally, in night, somebody from airport called us, he has the passport, thank god :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all, training start...
:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tobe continued..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;originally posted 2/15/07&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry></feed>