<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jalan-jalan</title><link href="http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/feeds/zimbabwe.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/</id><updated>2014-08-02T18:13:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Zimbabwe, part 2..</title><link href="http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/2014/08/02/zimbabwe-part-2/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-08-02T18:13:00+01:00</updated><author><name>onty</name></author><id>tag:travel.theprasojos.web.id,2014-08-02:2014/08/02/zimbabwe-part-2/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, I always put in my pray during Ramadhan, hoping that I can spend the
Ied Al Fitr celebration together with my family, but it turns out that
Allah gave me 'another' new family here in Zimbabwe :). Yes, I spend Ied
Al Fitr here with the big family of Indonesian citizens ( well, not that
big, only 40 people here&amp;nbsp;including the kids ... ). The preparation day
started with making and cooking Ketupat lebaran together..after searched
in youtube, I finally created my very first Ketupat :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="CAM01606" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/cam01606.jpg?w=180" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feels like&amp;nbsp;home with the family.&amp;nbsp;We close the day with&amp;nbsp;ifthaar together
at the embassy office. After isya' in Masjid Al-Abbas on Boeing street,
we got confirmation that the moon has been seen on South Africa, that
means it should be visible in Harare too, so the next day will be the
1st of Syawal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ied prayer started around 8.15. We went to Arcadia mosque, where we met
most of Indonesian people there. I went together within the same car
with the embassy staff. Here's our selfie picture from inside the car :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/cam01613.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Ied pray, everybody gathered around outside the mosque. They
provided some snacks and drinks for free for everybody in the mosque.
It's time for halal bihalal. I even met some Indonesian people I haven't
met before, Dr Widi and his family. They drove from Bulawayo directly to
Harare specially to celebrate the Ied al Fitr together with Indonesian
people in Harare :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/cam01609.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that day continued as usual, since it's Monday. No official holiday
for me :). It's different with in Indonesia, it's like nothing big going
on that day, it's just normal day, business as usual. That is 1 major
difference in celebrating Ied Al Fitr far away from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/08/cam01618.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, it's time to go back to Jakarta, and celebrate the Ied Al Fitr
together with my family. Happy belated Ied Al Fitr to all Muslims in the
world :)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Zimbabwe part 1..</title><link href="http://travel.theprasojos.web.id/2014/07/19/zimbabwe-part-1/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-19T21:13:00+01:00</updated><author><name>onty</name></author><id>tag:travel.theprasojos.web.id,2014-07-19:2014/07/19/zimbabwe-part-1/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Chance&amp;nbsp;to see the outside world is one of my reason to take&amp;nbsp;this job :).
Never ever crossed&amp;nbsp;in my mind before that I will visit this country. I
have heard about this country before &amp;nbsp;when economic crisis hit this
country around 2008. &amp;nbsp;1 trillion&amp;nbsp;dollar zimbabwe equals to 1 USD, such
an epic story. My impression first time I hit this country is that, it
looks like&amp;nbsp;Indonesia, on 1970's :) ( don't get me wrong, I see 1970's
picture of Indonesia in some&amp;nbsp;old movie, I wasn't born yet that day :p ).
If you see the buses, the people, and how the city looks like, then you
might end up with the same conclusion with me :D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/2014-06-20-13-52-22.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No pic hoax ? Here's one of the picture I took during my journey from
hotel to /// office. Unfortunately I don't have the picture for the old
buses (updated), but you can imagine inter-city bus, with full of bag
loaded on top of it. Yeah, one of the problem here is transportation.
Those buses seem to only pass once in a few hour. Once they passed,
there will be so many people waiting, together with their belongings. I
also see some people waive their hands on the streets looking for a car
lift. Not sure if it is safe to give them a lift, since I'm just a
foreigner here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;---- Updated&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the bus view in Harare..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/cam01478.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait, there's also tall building here in this country :). During my
first week here, /// put me on Crowne plaza hotel located on the city
centre, surrounded by few tall buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/2014-06-15-17-01-26.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See ? Not too bad, except the internet speed :D. I can only really
browse the internet on 5-6 AM in the morning. When I came back to hotel
from the office around 7-8, the internet speed is horrible. I waited so
long to open a webpage ( which then ended up with me closing the laptop
and go to sleep :p). Yeah, the infrastructure is not good here.
Telecommunications and Transportation, those 2 things need to be
improved first here before they want to go to the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--- Updated, here's the other city view of Harare..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/cam01484.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the good thing about this country is that, there's almost no
traffic jam :). We can go to the airport from /// office in about 30
minutes on daytime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/2014-06-25-08-51-41.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wider road with less cars, compare this to Jakarta :). And yes, I rarely seen
any motor bikes here, which is probably a good thing :D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the other good thing, Indonesia has its embassy here. So, I went
there to meet with the people and to introduce myself. It's good to have
Indonesian friends in this nowhere country :D, at least I can speak
bahasa again after so long. Feels like home, but not the real home :).
The embassy staff are very helpful, if you imagine that all government
officers are hard, rigid, then you are wrong. They are all very friendly
here. I went there almost every weekend, just to say hi, and to talk to
them. &amp;nbsp;And yes, they held a friendly 17an match to celebrate Indonesia's
independence day, where &amp;nbsp;I won Gaple match, with pak Tachsin Fernandi as
my co-player....:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="http://theprasojos.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/2014-06-21-16-19-29.jpg?h=100&amp;amp;w=500" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's only about 40 Indonesian people here in Zimbabwe, including the kids.
Not so much, but that makes them&amp;nbsp;big family together in a foreign
country :) If you are interested more, just invite their Facebook
account &amp;quot;Perwakin Harare&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, that is all for part 1, time to go back to the apartment and prepare
some meal for Ifthar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zimbabwe, July 19th, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="embassy"></category><category term="harare"></category><category term="indonesian embassy"></category><category term="zimbabwe"></category></entry></feed>